<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="PF">
    <class>
        <name>Bloodrager (Draconic Bloodline)</name>
        <hd>10</hd>
        <skills>Acrobatics, Climb, Craft, Handle Animal, Intimidate, Knowledge (arcana), Perception, Ride, Spellcraft, Survival, Swim</skills>
        <skillPoints>4</skillPoints>
        <wealth>3d6*10</wealth>
        <spellAbility></spellAbility>
        <autolevel level = "1">
            <bab>1</bab>
            <fort>2</fort>
            <ref>0</ref>
            <will>0</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,0,0,0,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Weapon and Armor Proficiency</name>
                <text>Bloodragers are proficient with all simple and martial weapons, light armor, medium armor, and shields (except tower shields). A bloodrager can cast bloodrager spells while wearing light armor or medium armor without incurring the normal arcane spell failure chance. This does not affect the arcane spell failure chance for arcane spells received from other classes. Like other arcane spellcasters, a bloodrager wearing heavy armor or wielding a shield incurs a chance of arcane spell failure if the spell in question has somatic components.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Bloodline</name>
                <text>Each bloodrager has a source of magic somewhere in his heritage that empowers his bloodrages, bonus feats, and bonus spells. Sometimes this source ref lects a distant blood relationship to a powerful being, or is due to an extreme event involving such a creature somewhere in his family’s past. Regardless of the source, this inf luence manifests in a number of ways. A bloodrager must pick one bloodline upon taking his first level of bloodrager. Once made, this choice cannot be changed.</text>
                <text>      When choosing a bloodline, the bloodrager’s alignment doesn’t restrict his choices. A good bloodrager could come from an abyssal bloodline, a celestial bloodline could beget an evil bloodrager generations later, a bloodrager from an infernal bloodline could be chaotic, and so on. Though his bloodline empowers him, it doesn’t dictate or limit his thoughts and behavior.</text>
                <text>      The bloodrager gains bloodline powers at 1st level, 4th level, and every 4 levels thereafter. The bloodline powers a bloodrager gains are described in his chosen bloodline. For all spell-like bloodline powers, treat the character’s bloodrager level as the caster level.</text>
                <text>      At 6th level and every 3 levels thereafter, a bloodrager receives one bonus feat chosen from a list specific to each bloodline. The bloodrager must meet the prerequisites for these bonus feats.</text>
                <text>      At 7th, 10th, 13th, and 16th levels, a bloodrager learns an additional spell derived from his bloodline. These spells are in addition to the number of spells given on Table 1–4. These spells cannot be exchanged for different spells at higher levels.</text>
                <text>      If the bloodrager takes levels in another class that grants a bloodline, the bloodlines must be the same type, even if that means that the bloodline of one of the classes must change. Subject to GM discretion, the bloodrager can change his previous bloodline to make them conform.</text>
                <text></text>
                <text>Draconic Bloodline</text>
                <text>At some point in your family’s history, a dragon interbred with your bloodline. Now, the sublime monster’s ancient power fuels your bloodrage.</text>
                <text>      Bonus Feats: Blind-Fight, Cleave, Great Fortitude, Improved Initiative, Power Attack, Skill Focus (Fly), Toughness.</text>
                <text>      Bonus Spells: Shield (7th), resist energy (10th), fly (13th), fear (16th).</text>
                <text>      Bloodline Powers: The power of dragons f lows through you and manifests in a number of ways. At 1st level, you must select a chromatic or metallic dragon type (see the table below). Once chosen, this type cannot be changed. A number of your bloodline powers deal damage and grant resistances based on your dragon type, as noted below.</text>
                <text>Dragon Type   Energy Type     Breath Shape</text>
                <text>Black         Acid            60-foot line</text>
                <text>Blue          Electiricity    60-foot line</text>
                <text>Green         Acid            30-foot cone</text>
                <text>Red           Fire            30-foot cone</text>
                <text>White         Cold            30-foot cone</text>
                <text>Brass         Fire            60-foot line</text>
                <text>Bronze        Electricity     60-foot line</text>
                <text>Copper        Acid            60-foot line</text>
                <text>Gold          Fire            30-foot cone</text>
                <text>Silver        Cold            30-foot cone</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Claws (Su)</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you grow claws. These claws are treated as natural weapons, allowing you to make two claw attacks as a full attack, using your full base attack bonus. These attacks each deal an amount of damage equal to 1d6 (1d4 if you are Small) + your Strength modifier. At 4th level, these claws are considered magic weapons for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction. At 8th level, the amount of damage increases to 1d8 (1d6 if you are Small) + your Strength modifier. At 12th level, these claws deal an additional 1d6 points of damage of your energy type on a hit.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Bloodrager Spells</name>
                <text>Bloodragers gain access to the following spells. While most of these spells are found in the Core Rulebook, those with superscripts are drawn from other sources. Those marked with an asterisk (*) appear in Chapter 4 of this book.</text>
                <text>      1st-Level Bloodrager Spells: Blade lash*, blurred movement*, break, burning hands, cause fear, chill touch, color spray, corrosive touch, ear-piercing scream, endure elements, enlarge person, expeditious retreat, feather fall, f lare burst, frostbite, hydraulic push, icicle dagger, jump, line in the sand*, long arm*, mage armor, magic missile, magic weapon, marid’s mastery, mirror strike, mount, mudball, phantom blood*, protection from chaos/ evil/good/law, ray of enfeeblement, ray of sickening, reduce person, returning weapon, shadow weapon, shield, shock shield, shocking grasp, stone fist, stone shield, strong wings, sundering shards*, thunderstomp*, touch of combustion, touch of gracelessness, touch of the sea, true strike, unerring weapon, warding weapon, wave shield*, web bolt, windy escape, winter feathers.</text>
                <text>      2nd-Level Bloodrager Spells: Ablative barrier, acid arrow, adhesive blood*, animal aspect, bear’s endurance, blindness/ deafness, blood armor*, blood blaze, boiling blood, brow gasher, bullet shield, bull’s strength, burning gaze, cat’s grace, certain grip, daze monster, death from below, defensive shock, delay pain, disfiguring touch, dust of twilight, eagle’ssplendor,elementaltouch,extremeflexibility*,falselife,fire breath, flaming sphere, frigid touch, ghoul touch, glitterdust, gust of wind, gusting sphere, imbue with elemental might, mirror image, molten orb*, protection from arrows, pyrotechnics, resist energy, scorching ray, see invisibility, shatter, slipstream, sonic scream*, spider climb, steal breath, stone call, stone discus*, touch of idiocy, unshakable chill.</text>
                <text>      3rd-Level Bloodrager Spells: Air geyser*, animal aspect (greater), aqueous orb, beast shape I, blood biography, blood scent, burrow, burst of speed, chain of perdition, cloak of winds, countless eyes, draconic reservoir, elemental aura, eruptive pustules, excruciating deformation, fire trail, fireball, firestream, flame arrow, fly, force hook charge, force punch, gloomblind bolts, haste, heroism, hold person, hostile levitation, howling agony, hydraulic torrent, keen edge, lightning bolt, locate weakness, magic weapon (greater), monstrous physique I, pain strike, paragon surge, phantom steed, protection from energy, rage, raging rubble, ray of exhaustion, resinous skin, silver darts*, sleet storm, slow, stinking cloud, thunderstomp (greater)*, twilight knife, undead anatomy I, vampiric touch, versatile weapon, vision of hell, water breathing, wind wall.</text>
                <text>      4th-Level Bloodrager Spells: Absorbing inhalation, ball lightning, beast shape II, bestow curse, black tentacles, calcific touch, confusion, contagion, crushing despair, detonate, dragon’s breath, earth glide, elemental body I, enervation, enlarge person (mass), false life (greater), fear, fire shield, firefall, f laming sphere (greater)*, ghost wolf , hellmouth lash, ice storm, monstrous physique II, moonstruck, pellet blast, phantasmal killer, reduce person (mass), ride the waves, river of wind, shocking image, shout, stoneskin, telekinetic charge, touch of slime, vermin shape I, vitriolic mist, volcanic storm, wall of fire, wall of ice, wall of sound, wreath of blades.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Bloodrage (Su)</name>
                <text>The bloodrager’s source of internal power grants him the ability to bloodrage. At 1st level, a bloodrager can bloodrage for a number of rounds per day equal to 4 + his Constitution modifier. At each level after 1st, he can bloodrage for 2 additional rounds per day. Temporary increases to Constitution (such as those gained from bloodraging or spells like bear’s endurance) don’t increase the total number of rounds that a bloodrager can bloodrage per day. The total number of rounds of bloodrage per day is renewed after resting for 8 hours, although these hours don’t need to be consecutive.</text>
                <text>A bloodrager can enter a bloodrage as a free action. While in a bloodrage, a bloodrager gains a +4 morale bonus to his Strength and Constitution, as well as a +2 morale bonus on Will saves. In addition, he takes a –2 penalty to Armor Class. The increase to Constitution grants the bloodrager 2 hit points per Hit Die, but these disappear when the bloodrage ends and are not lost first like temporary hit points. While bloodraging, a bloodrager cannot use any Charisma-, Dexterity-, or Intelligence-based skills (except Acrobatics, Fly, Intimidate, and Ride) or any ability that requires patience or concentration.</text>
                <text>A bloodrager can end his bloodrage as a free action. When the bloodrage ends, he’s fatigued for a number of rounds equal to twice the number of rounds spent in the bloodrage. A bloodrager cannot enter a new bloodrage while fatigued or exhausted, but can otherwise enter a bloodrage multiple times during a single encounter or combat. If a bloodrager falls unconscious, his bloodrage immediately ends, placing him in peril of death.</text>
                <text>Bloodrage counts as the barbarian’s rage class feature for the purpose of feat prerequisites, feat abilities, magic item abilities, and spell effects.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Fast Movement (Ex)</name>
                <text>A bloodrager’s base speed is faster than is normal for his race by 10 feet. This benefit applies only when he is wearing no armor, light armor, or medium armor, and not carrying a heavy load. Apply this bonus before modifying the bloodrager’s speed due to any armor worn or load carried. This bonus stacks with any other bonuses to the bloodrager’s base speed.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "2">
            <bab>2</bab>
            <fort>3</fort>
            <ref>0</ref>
            <will>0</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,0,0,0,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Uncanny Dodge (Ex)</name>
                <text>At 2nd level, a bloodrager can react to danger before his senses would normally allow him to do so. He cannot be caught f lat-footed, nor does he lose his Dexterity bonus to AC if the attacker is invisible. He still loses his Dexterity bonus to AC if immobilized. A bloodrager with this ability can still lose his Dexterity bonus to AC if an opponent successfully uses the feint action against him.</text>
                <text>If a bloodrager already possesses uncanny dodge from a different class, he automatically gains improved uncanny dodge (see below) instead.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "3">
            <bab>3</bab>
            <fort>3</fort>
            <ref>1</ref>
            <will>1</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,0,0,0,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Blood Sanctuary (Su)</name>
                <text>At 3rd level, due to the power of his blood, a bloodrager can stand confidently amid the effects of spells cast by himself or his allies. He gains a +2 bonus on saving throws against spells that he or an ally casts.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "4">
            <bab>4</bab>
            <fort>4</fort>
            <ref>1</ref>
            <will>1</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,1,0,0,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Blood Casting (Su)</name>
                <text>At 4th level, the bloodrager gains the ability to cast spells even while bloodraging. He can also cast these spells defensively and can attempt concentration checks for these spells while bloodraging. While bloodraging, he can cast and concentrate on only his bloodrager spells (see below); spells from other classes cannot be cast during this state.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Eschew Materials</name>
                <text>At 4th level, the bloodrager gains Eschew Materials as a bonus feat.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Spells</name>
                <text>Beginning at 4th level, a bloodrager gains the ability to cast a small number of arcane spells drawn from the bloodrager spell list (see page 22). To learn or cast a spell, a bloodrager must have a Charisma score equal to at least 10 + the spell level. He can cast spells he knows without preparing them ahead of time. The saving throw DC against a bloodrager’s spell is 10 + the spell level + the bloodrager’s Charisma modifier.</text>
                <text>Like other spellcasters, a bloodrager can cast only a certain number of spells of each level per day. His base daily spell allotment is given on Table 1–3. In addition, he receives bonus spells per day if he has a high Charisma score (see Table 1–3 on page 17 of the Pathfinder RPG Core Rulebook). The bloodrager does not need to prepare these spells in advance; he can cast any spell he knows at any time, assuming he hasn’t yet used up his allotment of spells per day for the spell’s level.</text>
                <text>The bloodrager’s selection of spells is limited. At 4th level, a bloodrager knows two 1st-level spells of his choice. A bloodrager gains more spells as he increases in level, as indicated on Table 1–4. Unlike spells per day, the number of spells a bloodrager knows is not affected by his Charisma score, but it is affected by any bonus spells he gains from his bloodline. At 8th level and every 3 levels thereafter, a bloodrager can choose to learn a new spell in place of one he already knows. This swap follows all the same rules as for a sorcerer.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Draconic Resistance (Ex)</name>
                <text>At 4th level, you gain resistance 5 against your energy type and a +1 natural armor bonus to AC. At 8th level, your energy resistance increases to 10 and your natural armor bonus increases to +2. At 16th level, your natural armor bonus increases to +4.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "5">
            <bab>5</bab>
            <fort>4</fort>
            <ref>1</ref>
            <will>1</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,1,0,0,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Improved Uncanny Dodge (Ex)</name>
                <text>At 5th level, a bloodrager can no longer be flanked. This defense denies rogues (or other classes with the sneak attack ability) the ability to sneak attack the bloodrager by f lanking him, unless the attacker has at least four more rogue levels (or levels in the class granting sneak attack) than the target has bloodrager levels.</text>
                <text>If a character already has uncanny dodge from another class, the levels from the classes that grant uncanny dodge stack when determining the minimum rogue level required to f lank the character.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "6">
            <bab>6</bab>
            <fort>5</fort>
            <ref>2</ref>
            <will>2</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,1,0,0,0</slots>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "7">
            <bab>7</bab>
            <fort>5</fort>
            <ref>2</ref>
            <will>2</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,1,1,0,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Damage Reduction (Ex)</name>
                <text>At 7th level, a bloodrager gains damage reduction. Subtract 1 from the damage the bloodrager takes each time he is dealt damage from a weapon or a natural attack. At 10th level, and every 3 levels thereafter, this damage reduction increases by 1 point. Damage reduction can reduce damage to 0, but not below 0.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "8">
            <bab>8</bab>
            <fort>6</fort>
            <ref>2</ref>
            <will>2</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,1,1,0,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Breath Weapon (Su)</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain a breath weapon that you can use once per day. This breath weapon deals 1d6 points of damage of your energy type per bloodrager level. Those caught in the area of your breath weapon can attempt a Ref lex saving throw for half damage. The DC of this save is equal to 10 + 1/2 your bloodrager level + your Constitution modifier. The shape of the breath weapon depends on your dragon type (as indicated on the above table). At 16th level, you can use this ability twice per day. At 20th level, you can use this ability three times per day.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "9">
            <bab>9</bab>
            <fort>6</fort>
            <ref>3</ref>
            <will>3</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,2,1,0,0</slots>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "10">
            <bab>10</bab>
            <fort>7</fort>
            <ref>3</ref>
            <will>3</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,2,1,0,0</slots>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "11">
            <bab>11</bab>
            <fort>7</fort>
            <ref>3</ref>
            <will>3</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,2,1,1,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Greater Bloodrage (Su)</name>
                <text>At 11th level, when a bloodrager enters a bloodrage, the morale bonus to his Strength and Constitution increases to +6 and the morale bonus on his Will saves increases to +3. In addition, upon entering a bloodrage, the bloodrager can apply the effects a bloodrager spell he knows of 2nd level or lower to himself. The spell must have a range of touch or personal. If the spell’s duration 3 is greater than 1 round, it instead lasts for the duration of the bloodrage. This use consumes a bloodrager spell slot, as if he had cast the spell; he must have the spell slot available to take advantage of this effect.</text>
                <text>Greater bloodrage counts as the barbarian’s greater rage ability for the purposes of feat prerequisites, feat abilities, magic item abilities, and spell effects.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "12">
            <bab>12</bab>
            <fort>8</fort>
            <ref>4</ref>
            <will>4</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,2,1,1,0</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Dragon Wings (Su)</name>
                <text>At 12th level, when entering a bloodrage, you can choose to have leathery wings grow from your back, giving you a f ly speed of 60 feet with average maneuverability. At 16th level, your fly speed increases to 80 feet with good maneuverability.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "13">
            <bab>13</bab>
            <fort>8</fort>
            <ref>4</ref>
            <will>4</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,3,2,1,1</slots>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "14">
            <bab>14</bab>
            <fort>9</fort>
            <ref>4</ref>
            <will>4</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,3,2,1,1</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Indomitable Will (Ex)</name>
                <text>At 14th level, a bloodrager gains a +4 bonus on Will saves to resist enchantment spells while bloodraging. This bonus stacks with all other modifiers, including the morale bonus on Will saves he also receives during his bloodrage.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "15">
            <bab>15</bab>
            <fort>9</fort>
            <ref>5</ref>
            <will>5</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,3,2,2,1</slots>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "16">
            <bab>16</bab>
            <fort>10</fort>
            <ref>5</ref>
            <will>5</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,3,3,2,1</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Dragon Form (Su)</name>
                <text>At 16th level, when entering a bloodrage, you can choose to take the form of your chosen dragon type (as form of the dragon II, but with good maneuverability, as you would gain from the dragon wings bloodrage power above).</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "17">
            <bab>17</bab>
            <fort>10</fort>
            <ref>5</ref>
            <will>5</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,4,3,2,1</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Tireless Bloodrage (Su)</name>
                <text>At 17th level, a bloodrager no longer becomes fatigued at the end of his bloodrage.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "18">
            <bab>18</bab>
            <fort>11</fort>
            <ref>6</ref>
            <will>6</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,4,3,2,2</slots>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "19">
            <bab>19</bab>
            <fort>11</fort>
            <ref>6</ref>
            <will>6</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,4,3,3,2</slots>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level = "20">
            <bab>20</bab>
            <fort>12</fort>
            <ref>6</ref>
            <will>6</will>
            <spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
            <slots>0,4,4,3,2</slots>
            <feature>
                <name>Mighty Bloodrage (Su)</name>
                <text>At 20th level, when a bloodrager enters a bloodrage, the morale bonus to his Strength and Constitution increases to +8, and the morale bonus on his Will saves increases to +4. Furthermore, the spell he can apply to himself at the beginning of a bloodrage due to the greater bloodrage class feature is not limited to only spells of 2nd level or lower.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Power of Wyrms (Su)</name>
                <text>At 20th level, you gain immunity to paralysis, sleep, and damage from your energy type. You also gain blindsense with a range of 60 feet. You have these benefits constantly, even while not bloodraging.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
    </class>
</compendium>
